# **QI CHEN**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **EDUCATION**

# BS of Computer Science, Dean's List

University of Memphis/TN/2011 - 2015

## **Platform by Per Scholas**

Specialized IT Training / NY/ 2019

Trained to understand and analyze the basics of Big Data and Hadoop technologies through hands-on activities, case studies, and group projects. Learned how to extract, scrub, and manipulate real-time and warehouse data using SQL & Java.

#### **SKILLS**

Java	
Python	
C++	
MySQL	
Hive	
Sqoop	
Oozie	
AWS	
VMWare	
MapReduce	
Hadoop	
Linux	
API: JDBC	
DECT	

#### **REFERENCES**

# John-Paul Wenger

Technical Support Lead
Dahua Technology

**W:** 562-704-6533 **C:** 562-646-6667 **E:** jp.wenger@dahuatech.com

(	646-598-1337	0	github.com/swordwielder
$\bowtie$	qchen125@gmail.com	in	linkedin.com/in/qifchen

#### **PROFILE**

Data and Analytics specialist with experience in surveillance security industry in tech roles with focus in Data Modeling, Scheduling, Big Data, and Data Distribution. Hold a BS Degree in Computer Science with four years of programming and 10 years of customer service experience utilizing software from Google Analytics to Salesforce.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### INDEPENDENT DEVELOPER

Freelance / New York, NY / 2019

- $\cdot$  Created a Discord bot that gives real live weather, crypto and stock data through API calls in Python
- $\cdot$  Implemented a REST API with GET, DELETE, and POST methods in Python for sporting best
- · Created chenpost.com using AWS S3 bucket with HTML, CSS and JS

# PRODUCT ENGINEER, TECHNICAL WRITER & CONTENT MANAGER

Dahua Tech USA Inc. / Irvine, CA / 2015 - 2018

- · Updated and maintained Dahuawiki.com to provide better technical support to the customers including adding YouTube tutorials with 7000 daily hits on website tracked through Google Analytics.
- · Hardware testing/support for clients including but not limited to NVRs, DVRs, IP Cameras, and Analog Cameras via Salesforce.

#### **COMPUTER SCIENCE TUTOR**

Computer Science Learning Center, University of Memphis / Memphis, TN / 2014 - 2015

- · Helped students with coursework and checked coding errors
- Taught & Mentored high school students with interests in Computer Science in the field of game development using Ren'Py

#### **TECHNICAL CONSULTANT**

ITS Service Desk, University of Memphis / Memphis, TN / 2013 - 2015

 $\cdot$  Assisted campus students with troubleshooting U of M services including E-learn, UMDrive, portal via Helpdesk using campus SupportSuite software